Arizona Civil Liberties Union records, 1958-1968
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Arizona Civil Liberties Union records, 1958-1968
AZ 182
Arizona Civil Liberties Union.
Correspondence, financial reports, minutes of meetings, publications, clippings, tape recordings of radio broadcasts, and material on various local cases and projects. Includes papers relating to its establishment and operation in connection with the national civil liberties movement, and the Arizona Legislative Coordinating Committee, an independent ad hoc committee formed to encourage passage of constructive State legislation in the field of civil rights and liberties.
1.6 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Organization
This collection is organized into four series:
Series I: Correspondence, 1958-1967
Series II: Records and Publications, 1959-1967
Series III: Projects and Cases, 1959-1966
Series IV: Coordinating Committee Materials, 1961-1968
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, financial reports, minutes of meetings, publications, clippings, tape recordings of radio broadcasts, and material on various local cases and projects. Includes papers relating to its establishment and operation in connection with the national civil liberties movement, and the Arizona Legislative Coordinating Committee, an independent ad hoc committee formed to encourage passage of constructive State legislation in the field of civil rights and liberties. Local cases concern issues such as academic freedom, prayer in schools, vagrancy, and segregation. Also includes Arizona Civil Liberties Union Legislative Bulletin, 1962-1968.
Access Terms
Arizona Legislative Coordinating Committee -- Records and correspondence.
Civil rights -- Arizona
Academic freedom -- Arizona
Prayer in the public schools -- United States
Prayer in the public schools -- United States
Vagrancy -- Arizona
Segregation -- Arizona
Liberty
Arizona -- Politics and government
Correspondence
Reports
Case Files
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence, 1958-1967
  Includes letters from: Arthur Goldberg, Carl Hayden, James Roosevelt, Morris K. Udall, and Stewart Udall. Also contains Box of Membership Cards.
  - Correspondence-General. 1958-1967 (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
  - Correspondence-With the American Civil Liberties Union. 1958-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
- Series II: Records and Publications, 1959-1967
  - Constitution and By-laws. 1959-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Elections. 1959-1963, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - State Executive Board: Minutes of Meetings. 1959-1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Treasurers' Reports. 1959-1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Publicity, News Releases, Clippings. 1959-1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Southern Area: Minutes of Meetings (Board of Directors). 1959-1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Southern Area: Miscellaneous Papers. 1959-1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Northern AreaL Newsletter No. 1-6; Reprot of Legal Counsel. 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Northern Area: Minutes of Meetings. 1959-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Series III: Projects and Cases, 1959-1966
  - "Arrest Pamphlet." 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Birth Control. 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Corbett-Strickler Case (Draft Deferment). 1961 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Elfbrandt Case (Arizona Loyalty Oath). 1961-1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - House Un-American Activities Committee. 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Koch Case (Academic Freedom). 1961 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - McEwan Case (Academic Freedom). 1961 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Mine-Mill Case. 1962 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Miscegnation Law, Arizona. 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Cases. 1961-1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "Operation Correction" and "Operation Abolition." 1961 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "Peyote Case." 1960 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Police Relations. 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Prayers in Schools. 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Public Defender Law. 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Registration of Felons. 1959, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Segregation. 1959-1967 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - University of Arizona Student Symposium on Communism. 1962 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Vagrancy and Loitering (Correspondence). 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Vagrancy and Loitering (Clippings, Miscellaneous Materials). (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Various (CARTT, School Resource Officers, Public Accommodations). (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Series IV: Coordinating Committee Materials, 1961-1968
  Includes: Tape-Radio Broadcasts on "Operation Correction" by Tucson KTKT, 1962; Tape-Radio Broadcast (Feldman) by Tucson Station KTAN, 1961.
  - Legislative Coordinating Committee: Adminsitrative Papers, Meetings. 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Legislative Coordinating Committee: Correspondence. 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Legislative Coordinating Committee: Miscellaneous Legislative Material (Bills, Precinct Maps, etc.). 1961-1968 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - ACLU Legislative Bulletin, v. 1-7. 1962-1968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Material ( includes Clippings). 1961-1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Miscellaneous Material). 1961-1968 (Box 4, Folder 6)